MOHAMMED ZAHEER

CONTACT

Address : Vellore, TN 632001 **Phone :** +91-7418704202

Email:

zaheermohammed410@gmail.com

SKILLS

- · Risk Management
- · Vulnerability Assessment
- Compliance
- Threat Hunting
- Email Security
- Penetration Testing
- Report Writing
- Embedded Linux Security
- · ARM exploitation and security
- · Docker container security
- ISO 21434
- SAEJ3061
- API security
- Mobile Security
- Python
- · Bash Scripting

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering: Electrical, Electronics Engineering Technologies, 06/2016

Anna University - Vellore

Percentage - 76%

High School Diploma: 05/2012 Voorhees Higher Seconday School -

Vellore

Percentage - 71%

SSLC, 05/2010

Voorhees Higher Secondary School - Vellore

vellore

Percentage - 82%

CERTIFICATIONS

• EC Council - Certified Ethical Hacker

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate cyber security professional with more than 5 years of experience in Automobile Cyber Security (Threat Analysis and Risk Assessment, Threat Modeling, Security Concept Development, Implementation of Security Concepts) and IT Cyber Security (Security Monitoring, Threat Hunting, Vulnerability Management, VAPT).

Never give up person with **positive frame of mind**. Eager to work as a team and contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Self-Motivated to learn, grow and excel in Automotive Cyber Security.

WORK HISTORY

Cybersecurity Engineer, 05/2022 to Current Magna Electronics - Pune, India Project - Fisker and Stellantis ADAS

- Working in ADAS projects
- Covering entire cybersecurity lifecycle of the project following ISO21434
- Eastablishing the automated process vulnerability management in compliance with the ISO21434: Clause 8 - Continual Cyber Security Activities
- Written Incident response management process and implemented the process
- Working with software & systems teams to implement functionalities incorporating cybersecurity concepts
- Working along with manufacturing team to assist them on production security, key management
- Working in blackduck software composition analysis tool to scan the software binaries post build

Senior Software Engineer - CyberSecurity, 03/2021 to 05/2022 Valeo India Private Limited - Chennai, India

Project - Daimler Telematics Control Unit

- Lead the project in collaboration with customer and adhere to their timelines, following agile methodologies
- Performed preliminary risk analysis based on the RFQ documents provided by the customer
- Have done the Threat analysis and Risk assessment using stride model.
- Wrote the Damage scenarios with respect to the road user perspective leveraging the key aspects such as financial, operational, safety, privacy
- Accommodating the UNECE threat references in the risk assessment and in lining with UNECE WP29, UN R155(CSMS) cyber security
- Written the security concepts or security fixes for the identified threats
- Delivered the required security concepts to the customer at mentioned timeline

 Advanced Android Application Exploitation- TheHacktivists

COURSES

- · Cisco Certified Network Administrator
- Practical Ethical Hacking Pursuing

- Managing and writing complex security requirements on IBM DOORS utilizing DOORS attributes
- Writing V2X related security requirements
- In lining with software teams throughout the Project Lifecycle
- Involved in key aspects during the implementation of software
- Working knowledge on ISO 21434 and SAE J3061
- Assisting team on error corrections and on streamlining the risk assessment process

IT-Analyst -SOC- Vulnerability Management, 01/2019 to 03/2021 Lennox India Technology Center - Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Performed Manual and Automated Security Testing for Web Application
 & Web Services
- Planning, Conducting and reporting Vulnerability and risk assessment of applications
- Ensuring the security coverage for all the applications of organization
- Identification of Injection, Business logic, Authentication, Session Management, etc.
- Related flaws in applications and encasing attack scenarios and associated risk to business
- Risk associated with vulnerability explained to the project team for better.
- Provided mitigation for the identified application vulnerabilities and worked with the project team for the remediation.
- Understanding in data privacy and data security regulatory requirements or framework such as HIPAA, GDPR, NIST, HITRUST, SOC II, etc.)
- Working knowledge and exposure of IT Governance, Risk Management, and Compliance practices
- Communicate any potential risks or guidance, to the Division, with regards to GDPR (from Article 29 Working Party, or Capita Group Data Protection Officer)
- Provide recommendations to the Division, on Data Protection related initiatives or awareness campaigns
- Have streamlined the infrastructure vulnerability assessment process and designed the architecture
- Performing vulnerability scans on the servers and other network devices via Nexpose from Rapid 7 & Nessus from Tenable
- Prioritizing the vulnerabilities identified, Create Remediation Projects with Incident Ticket and assign it to Stake Holders for Remediation.
- Evaluate Risk to Perform Upgrade, Apply Patch & to Remediate Configuration Vulnerabilities.
- Performing PCI scans every quarter and submitting the report to external auditor for compliance
- Validate the Closure with the Scheduled Scan.
- Involved in ensuring the disaster recovery and business continuity plans are up-to-date and exercised periodically. Produce all documentations related to conducted DRPs.
- Having a knowledge in performing internal active directory pentesting
- Hands on experience in webapplication testing tools like burpsuite, sqlmap, Netsparker and webinspect

IT Analyst - SOC, 04/2018 to 01/2019 Lennox India Technology Center - Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Monitor the organization's network for security threats & investigate security violations
- Performing Attack-Based threat hunting and Data based threat hunting in SIEM

- Sound Knowledge in social engineering attacks
- Analyzing email related threats such as Phishing, Social engineering & Scam's
- Conducting phishing and scam simulations with self defined tools to spread awareness among users
- Creating quarterly trend report on phishing and scam
- Organizing and Implementing the information security awareness program's
- · Having knowledge in windows active directory attacks
- Linux suspicious events monitoring and root cause analysis
- Azure security center, Active directory monitoring & root cause analysis
- 0365 email security monitoring
- Creating use cases on various platforms such as Linux, Windows, DLP,
 Firewall in SIEM
- Expertise in various security tools like Palo Alto UTM, Varonis Endpoint Threat Detection, McAfee ePO, Cimtrak FIM, Barracuda SPAM Filtering FW and SkyHigh CASB

Process Executive, 12/2016 to 03/2018 **Infosys** - Chennai, Tamilnadu

- Working in Security Incident and Event Monitoring SIEM platform Security Analytics
- · Working in FireEye and GRA Tool
- Monitoring various event sources for possible intrusion and determine the severity of threat
- Hauling Ad hoc report for various event sources and, customized reports and scheduled reports as per requirements
- Monitoring security incidents from multiple devices such as Symantec Antivirus, Check Point Firewall, NIPS, AD, Bluecoat, Cisco switch and Cisco ACS
- Monitor RSA SA dashboards to keep track of real time security events, health of end point devices
- Collecting the logs of all network devices and analyze the logs to investigate the suspicious activities
- Investigate the security logs, mitigation strategies and Responsible for preparing Generic Security incident report
- Analyze the Malware with tools like sysinternals
- Creating daily/weekly/monthly reports for baselines on critical incidents